<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mindfulness on Schafe sind bessere Rasenmäher</title><link>/categories/mindfulness/</link><description>Recent content in Mindfulness on Schafe sind bessere Rasenmäher</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 19:09:38 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/mindfulness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Being centered - physically and temporally</title><link>/mindfulness/being-centered-physically-and-temporally/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 19:09:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>/mindfulness/being-centered-physically-and-temporally/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the longest time I&amp;rsquo;ve always interpreted &lt;em>being centered&lt;/em> as something mostly physical. A strong stance. Nobody can shake you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are also some mental aspects to it: feeling confident, having full acceptance of your strengths and weaknesses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But one aspect never popped up until now: being centered temporally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not thinking about what happened yesterday, or even in the conversation you had just now. Also not thinking ahead to what needs to be done tomorrow or worrying about things in the future.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tying shoelaces</title><link>/mindfulness/tying-shoelaces/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 19:09:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>/mindfulness/tying-shoelaces/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to be more mindful during the day and keep my focus on the task at hand. Whenever I catch my thoughts wandering off, I gently pull them back into the present moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;aside>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s going great. I just spilt a glass of water while setting up the laptop for this post, because I was pondering what to write. 😅&lt;/p>&lt;/aside>

&lt;p>I (re)started this journey rather recently, &lt;strong>but&lt;/strong> I discovered that I&amp;rsquo;ve already been tying my shoelaces mindfully for the last year or so, ever since I learned about the &lt;em>Granny Knot&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>