<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mindfulness on Schafe sind bessere Rasenmäher</title><link>/mindfulness/</link><description>Recent content in Mindfulness on Schafe sind bessere Rasenmäher</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 08:41:38 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/mindfulness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Looking for obstacles</title><link>/mindfulness/looking-for-obstacles/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 08:41:38 +0100</pubDate><guid>/mindfulness/looking-for-obstacles/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve published anything on this site. Every now and then an idea pops into my head that sparks a flame of excitement. Sadly these don&amp;rsquo;t last long enough for me to sit down and actually write them out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have tons of ideas in my notes, but the excitement often leaves me once I&amp;rsquo;ve written down a few words as a reminder.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Part of it is, that so many of these things have been said before, often by people that are much better wordsmiths than I am. But another big part of it is that I&amp;rsquo;m really exhausted.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>One step at a time #3</title><link>/mindfulness/one-step-at-a-time-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 11:56:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>/mindfulness/one-step-at-a-time-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>I think it&amp;rsquo;s time to reflect on the progress I&amp;rsquo;ve made the last few weeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Very interesting right from the start. I just copied the last post as a template and my initial intent was removing everything and starting from scratch. But now as I look through the headers, I think I want to think more deeply about the individual topics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with a quick brain dump: I&amp;rsquo;ve been very dissatisfied with the last few weeks. Things have been stressful and chaotic. I haven&amp;rsquo;t meditated, I&amp;rsquo;ve lost my temper at least once and I noticed that I&amp;rsquo;m struggling with quite a few of my new habits.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>One step at a time #2</title><link>/mindfulness/one-step-at-a-time-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 11:16:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>/mindfulness/one-step-at-a-time-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>I think it&amp;rsquo;s time to reflect on the progress I&amp;rsquo;ve made the last few weeks. I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to do these updates more regularly, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing other things instead.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="toc">
 &lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#positive-phrasing">Positive phrasing&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#finding-joy-in-mundane-things">Finding joy in mundane things&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#battling-fomo--deliberate-media-consumption">Battling FOMO / Deliberate media consumption&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#getting-angryat-my-kids">Getting angry&amp;hellip;at my kids&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#listening-to-my-body">Listening to my body&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#meditating">Meditating&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;/div>

&lt;h2 id="positive-phrasing">Positive phrasing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;ve been following along, you might be confused by the number &lt;em>2&lt;/em> in the title. I renamed the previous post from &lt;em>old habits die hard&lt;/em> to &lt;em>one step at a time&lt;/em>, because it sounds a tad more positive.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Emotional contagion</title><link>/mindfulness/emotional-contagion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 09:30:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>/mindfulness/emotional-contagion/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sometimes we Germans have nice descriptive words for things. One of these words is &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Mitgefühl&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> &amp;ndash; compassion. However, if you split it into it&amp;rsquo;s constituent words and translate them, you&amp;rsquo;ll end up with &amp;ldquo;with feeling&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;with&amp;rdquo; as in togetherness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a sense, from the words that make up &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Mitgefühl&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>, it&amp;rsquo;s much closer to &lt;em>empathy&lt;/em>, even if we Germans do not use it that way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Generally, being compassionate and empathic are considered good traits.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The magic of being humble</title><link>/mindfulness/the-magic-of-being-humble/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 21:30:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>/mindfulness/the-magic-of-being-humble/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve had a low-level fascination with knots since I was a little kid. Now, ever since I learned the &lt;a href="../tying-shoelaces">Ian Knot&lt;/a>, I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to look into more knots and try and learn them. I got it in my head today to build new bows for my kids, so of course I first wanted to learn how to tie a knot for a bowstring.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not even sure if I found the right thing, but I stumbled upon the &lt;a href="https://www.animatedknots.com/bowline-knot">Bowline Knot&lt;/a>. I found a guide on &lt;a href="https://www.animatedknots.com">https://www.animatedknots.com&lt;/a> and pretty much got stuck on the site for the rest of the day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>One step at a time #1</title><link>/mindfulness/one-step-at-a-time-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 22:09:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>/mindfulness/one-step-at-a-time-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Alright people! Time for the nitty-gritty!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My last few posts might have made me seem like a Zen-master, so get ready for the truth! 😅&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is meant to be an objective retrospective of how I&amp;rsquo;m doing on my way to being more mindful. As objective as I can be about myself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are however a few problems with this approach.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The most obvious one being, that I haven&amp;rsquo;t defined any goals I want to reach.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Positive Phrasing</title><link>/mindfulness/positive-phrasing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 21:09:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>/mindfulness/positive-phrasing/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Ah fuck, I still need to put the dishes into the dishwasher.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Man, I hate these meetings.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Kill me already. I don&amp;rsquo;t wanna&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been reminded of something my boss told me a few years ago.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The product I was working on at that time was &lt;strong>legacy code&lt;/strong> (queue scary sound effects). Horrible, messy code that was written more than two decades ago.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One component in particular was &lt;em>the&lt;/em> text book example of all the worst practices you can think of.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A blast from the past</title><link>/mindfulness/a-blast-from-the-past/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 17:09:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>/mindfulness/a-blast-from-the-past/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m still reading &lt;em>Reconciliation: Healing the inner child&lt;/em> by Thich Nhat Hanh and trying to slowly adjust my day-to-day habits to be more mindful. The latest exercise I tried was meditating and talking to my 5-year old self.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I haven&amp;rsquo;t meditated in a while and I&amp;rsquo;ve never been good at visualization techniques. Both very good reasons to give it a try. So I sat down yesterday for ten minutes and tried to establish contact to a 5-year old version of myself.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Being centered - physically and temporally</title><link>/mindfulness/being-centered-physically-and-temporally/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 19:09:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>/mindfulness/being-centered-physically-and-temporally/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the longest time I&amp;rsquo;ve always interpreted &lt;em>being centered&lt;/em> as something mostly physical. A strong stance. Nobody can shake you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are also some mental aspects to it: feeling confident, having full acceptance of your strengths and weaknesses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But one aspect never popped up until now: being centered temporally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not thinking about what happened yesterday, or even in the conversation you had just now. Also not thinking ahead to what needs to be done tomorrow or worrying about things in the future.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tying shoelaces</title><link>/mindfulness/tying-shoelaces/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 19:09:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>/mindfulness/tying-shoelaces/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to be more mindful during the day and keep my focus on the task at hand. Whenever I catch my thoughts wandering off, I gently pull them back into the present moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;aside>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s going great. I just spilt a glass of water while setting up the laptop for this post, because I was pondering what to write. 😅&lt;/p>&lt;/aside>

&lt;p>I (re)started this journey rather recently, &lt;strong>but&lt;/strong> I discovered that I&amp;rsquo;ve already been tying my shoelaces mindfully for the last year or so, ever since I learned about the &lt;em>Granny Knot&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mindful Parenting #4 - Noticing first benefits</title><link>/mindfulness/mindful-parenting-4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 19:09:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>/mindfulness/mindful-parenting-4/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve only been back on the Mindfulness train a few days, but I&amp;rsquo;m already noticing so many small things.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="toc">
 &lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#less-things-break">Less things break&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#consuming-less-media">Consuming less media&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#reconnecting-with-my-body">Reconnecting with my body&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#staying-calm">Staying calm&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bonus-tackling-my-fears">Bonus: tackling my fears&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#what-now">What now?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;/div>

&lt;h2 id="less-things-break">Less things break&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s kinda obvious in hindsight, but less things break when you&amp;rsquo;re being more careful. I&amp;rsquo;m not deliberately trying to be more careful, but whenever I can I try to keep myself in the moment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mindful Parenting #3 - Intuitive Friendship</title><link>/mindfulness/mindful-parenting-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 19:09:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>/mindfulness/mindful-parenting-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today I had the chance to observe this kind of &lt;em>instant friendship&lt;/em> forming, the way only kids seem to be capable of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re still on vacation and went out for lunch nearby. Next to the restaurant was a playground with a small wooden locomotive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;This is Molly&amp;rdquo;, my older son proclaimed as he sat behind the steering wheel. His younger brother of course playing along as a passenger.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re reading Jim Button together, so I immediately knew what he was talking about. He also kinda addressed a nearby mom, who looked very confused. I explained that it&amp;rsquo;s the little locomotive from Jim Button.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ramblings #1 - Unhealthy media consumption</title><link>/mindfulness/ramblings-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 22:09:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>/mindfulness/ramblings-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not the first person to notice this, nor am I the first person to write about it, but &lt;strong>not everything that is meant to help you relax is healthy&lt;/strong>. And I&amp;rsquo;m not even talking about drugs, but rather movies, TV shows or video games.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of all these things and there&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong with spending a relaxed evening in front of the TV. I&amp;rsquo;d go as far as to say there&amp;rsquo;s nothing particularly wrong with spending a whole week with a captivating video game.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mindful Parenting #2</title><link>/mindfulness/mindful-parenting-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 12:09:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>/mindfulness/mindful-parenting-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Things I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed so far:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I&amp;rsquo;m often annoyed when my kids want to talk to me. I&amp;rsquo;m usually already doing something else.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I&amp;rsquo;m more open to pay attention to my younger son. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s favoritism, although things are definitely easier with him. He plays a lot by himself and is more emotionally balanced&amp;hellip;for now.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No matter how hard I try, there will be times where I simply cannot attend to my kids. Work needs to be done, bills paid, groceries need to be bought and prepared. Not everything can happen when the kids are in bed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A bit ashamed that I only think about this now, but I&amp;rsquo;ve known for a long time that I&amp;rsquo;m susceptible to the emotions of other people. My older son becomes angry very quickly right now and that triggers me.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Things I can do:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mindful Parenting #1</title><link>/mindfulness/mindful-parenting-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 21:09:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>/mindfulness/mindful-parenting-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been angry a lot these last few weeks. I&amp;rsquo;ve been carrying a great big burning ball of anger inside me that threatens to burst out. Occasionally it does, too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My older child is now about 4.5 years old. He&amp;rsquo;s craving autonomy and control. Control over everything: his body, his parents, his brother, his surroundings&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s maddening. He does so many small things that drive me &lt;strong>crazy&lt;/strong>!!!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But ultimately these are all just small things.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>