<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Autobiography on Schafe sind bessere Rasenmäher</title><link>/tags/autobiography/</link><description>Recent content in Autobiography on Schafe sind bessere Rasenmäher</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 12:59:46 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/autobiography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gaming on Linux</title><link>/tech/gaming-on-linux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 12:59:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>/tech/gaming-on-linux/</guid><description>This is the 3rd part of a series where I rant about how I ended up with Linux as my daily driver.
The other parts can be found here:
How I learned how to use a PC How I came to love Linux Gaming on Linux This whole series was inspired by From Windows Fidelity to Linux Liberty: My Computing Evolution, a blog post by SudoMistress.
The final piece I needed to take the plunge on daily driving Linux was gaming.</description></item><item><title>How I came to love Linux</title><link>/tech/how-i-came-to-love-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 16:05:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>/tech/how-i-came-to-love-linux/</guid><description>This is the 2nd part of a series where I rant about how I ended up with Linux as my daily driver.
The other parts can be found here:
How I learned how to use a PC How I came to love Linux Gaming on Linux This whole series was inspired by From Windows Fidelity to Linux Liberty: My Computing Evolution, a blog post by SudoMistress.
I can&amp;rsquo;t exactly remember the first time I heard about this mystical alternative OS Linux.</description></item><item><title>How I learned to use a PC</title><link>/tech/how-i-learned-to-use-a-pc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 12:41:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>/tech/how-i-learned-to-use-a-pc/</guid><description>This is the 1st part of a series where I rant about how I ended up with Linux as my daily driver.
The other parts can be found here:
How I learned how to use a PC How I came to love Linux Gaming on Linux This whole series was inspired by From Windows Fidelity to Linux Liberty: My Computing Evolution, a blog post by SudoMistress.
When I was 10, my mom decided that we too needed a PC in our household.</description></item><item><title>Miez Attack, or how I got a job with a game about shooting cats</title><link>/tech/miez-attack/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 20:07:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>/tech/miez-attack/</guid><description>Back in 2015, after I had graduated from university, I was looking for jobs. I had a major in Physics, but my heart was no longer in it. Instead I wanted to write computer programs. After writing countless applications and receiving a few rejections (and a whole bunch of nothing), I finally hit a breakthrough. A small local company was willing to invite me for an interview.
It was in August of 2015, which I remember very well, because it was an incredibly hot day and I came fully armored in a suit1.</description></item></channel></rss>