<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Games on Schafe sind bessere Rasenmäher</title><link>/categories/games/</link><description>Recent content in Games on Schafe sind bessere Rasenmäher</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 21:26:19 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The day I fell out of love with Lumines...</title><link>/posts/the-day-i-fell-out-of-love-with-lumines/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 21:26:19 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-day-i-fell-out-of-love-with-lumines/</guid><description>&lt;p>&amp;hellip;was yesterday. 😅&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even back on the PSP, I always wanted to play Lumines, because it looked like an refreshing tetris-like puzzler to me. For me, this was before digital downloads &amp;ndash; at least PSN downloads, so I never ended up getting it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But my excitement rekindled when I saw that a Remaster arrived on the Nintendo Switch. And I spent countless hours in &lt;em>Challenge Mode&lt;/em>, trying to get to Level 100.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reminiscing About Classic Violent Games</title><link>/posts/reminiscing-about-classic-violent-games/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 20:49:26 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/reminiscing-about-classic-violent-games/</guid><description>&lt;p>I had trouble getting to sleep last night and my mind kept returning to games that I&amp;rsquo;d call &lt;em>classic&lt;/em>. I was born in 1987, so my definition will most likely differ from yours. Also, after finishing this list I realized that my brain got stuck on violent games. There&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of classic games left that I&amp;rsquo;m not going to talk about here.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="toc">
 &lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#resident-evil-2-1998">Resident Evil 2 (1998)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#quake-ii-1997">Quake II (1997)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#half-life-1998">Half-Life (1998)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#quake-1996">Quake (1996)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#unreal-1997">Unreal (1997)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#resident-evil-remake-2002">Resident Evil Remake (2002)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#hitman-codename-47-2000">Hitman: Codename 47 (2000)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;/div>

&lt;h2 id="resident-evil-2-1998">Resident Evil 2 (1998)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With the release of Resident Evil 2 Remake, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but enforce the &lt;strong>1998&lt;/strong> whenever I mention this game. I really enjoyed the remake, but it will never take the place of the original game (other than Resident Evil Remake, which you&amp;rsquo;ll find further down).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nightmare Frames (2022)</title><link>/posts/nightmare-frames-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 19:42:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/nightmare-frames-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Nightmare Frames&lt;/strong> by &lt;em>Postmodern Adventures&lt;/em> might be one of the best Lovecraftian horror games I&amp;rsquo;ve played so far.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It starts out as a pretty slow burn, but that&amp;rsquo;s alright for the horror genre. Once it&amp;rsquo;s got it&amp;rsquo;s hooks into you, it becomes really hard to put down. With two kids and a daytime job, I only get a few hours to myself every evening. If not for that, I can guarantee that I would have finished this in a single sitting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unpacking (2021)</title><link>/posts/unpacking-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 22:25:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/unpacking-2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is an amazing game with lots of heart. And very relaxing. As the title suggest you&amp;rsquo;re unpacking moving boxes and placing the unpacked items in absolutely beautiful pixel-art rooms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Coming fresh off of &lt;strong>Return to Monkey Island&lt;/strong> I clicked through the first few stages very quickly. But even so I started placing items more deliberately and grouping matching objects (e.g. books) together. I also quickly noticed recurring items, which the unnamed (and unseen) person keeps between places.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Return to Monkey Island (2022)</title><link>/posts/return-to-monkey-island-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 21:13:57 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/return-to-monkey-island-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s something I didn&amp;rsquo;t think we&amp;rsquo;d ever get: a new Monkey Island from Ron Gilbert. And as expected it fits in perfectly with the first two Monkey Island games.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My first contact with the Monkey Island series was with &lt;strong>The Curse of Monkey Island&lt;/strong>. I did not know at that time that it was the third entry in the series, but I remember enjoying the humor and slapstick. I didn&amp;rsquo;t get much further than the second chapter as a kid, although I finished it sometime later with a walkthrough. I tried to get through it about a year or so ago, but got stuck again in the second chapter, although on a different problem. I distinctly remember solving that on my own as a kid, but for the life of me couldn&amp;rsquo;t remember the solution.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>