<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Schafe sind bessere Rasenm칛her</title><link>/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Schafe sind bessere Rasenm칛her</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 13:43:38 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Who are we archiving for?</title><link>/posts/who-are-we-archiving-for/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 13:43:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/who-are-we-archiving-for/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://archive.org">Archive.org&lt;/a> has been through a lot of trouble in the last few weeks. Multiple DDoS attacks, a huge leak of sensitive data and constant legal trouble.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can remember neither the author, nor in which context specifically I ran across the following statement. It went something like this.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re obsessed with preserving content for &amp;ldquo;the future&amp;rdquo;, but there&amp;rsquo;s no rhyme or reason as to what we want to archive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Imagine digging up Pharaoh Ramses&amp;rsquo; shopping list.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Weekly wrap-up - April 04</title><link>/posts/weekly-wrapup-2024-04-04/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 21:09:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/weekly-wrapup-2024-04-04/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve been up to this last week.&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">&lt;/nav>

&lt;h2 id="gaming">Gaming&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After a long drought without gaming (the little one kept going to bed well after 21:30), I finally found the time for a few hours of gaming with only minor interruptions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I decided to finally take the plunge and play &lt;strong>Firewatch&lt;/strong>. Reviews were very positive when the game came out, but I had originally put it on the &lt;em>never, ever&lt;/em> pile after not getting to it for &lt;strong>8 years&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rediscovering the Hungarian language with a children's book</title><link>/posts/rediscovering-the-hungarian-language/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 21:09:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/rediscovering-the-hungarian-language/</guid><description>&lt;p>2023 hasn&amp;rsquo;t been a big reading year for me. I tend to alternate very heavily between watching movies and tv shows, playing videogames and reading books. This year I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing a lot of videogames with what little free time I have.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nevertheless, I do have a candidate for my &lt;em>book of the year 2023&lt;/em>: &lt;strong>A majom mam치ja&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;figure>
 &lt;img src="cover.webp" alt="The cover for A majom mam치ja." />
 &lt;figcaption>The cover for A majom mam치ja.&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Helltrain - My favorite band nobody knows</title><link>/posts/helltrain-my-favorite-band-nobody-knows/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 10:42:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/helltrain-my-favorite-band-nobody-knows/</guid><description>&lt;p>I initially intended to post a few songs on Mastodon and talk about my history with &lt;a href="https://helltrain.bandcamp.com">Helltrain&lt;/a>, but I quickly learned that this would be better suited to a blog post. So here we are&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve had Helltrain stuck in my ears for about a week. In particular this morning the chorus to &lt;em>Route 666&lt;/em> was stuck on repeat, so I tortured my kids with a bit of &amp;ldquo;Dad music&amp;rdquo; while prepping breakfast. 游때&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The day I fell out of love with Lumines...</title><link>/posts/the-day-i-fell-out-of-love-with-lumines/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 21:26:19 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-day-i-fell-out-of-love-with-lumines/</guid><description>&lt;p>&amp;hellip;was yesterday. 游땐&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even back on the PSP, I always wanted to play Lumines, because it looked like an refreshing tetris-like puzzler to me. For me, this was before digital downloads &amp;ndash; at least PSN downloads, so I never ended up getting it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But my excitement rekindled when I saw that a Remaster arrived on the Nintendo Switch. And I spent countless hours in &lt;em>Challenge Mode&lt;/em>, trying to get to Level 100.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reminiscing About Classic Violent Games</title><link>/posts/reminiscing-about-classic-violent-games/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 20:49:26 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/reminiscing-about-classic-violent-games/</guid><description>&lt;p>I had trouble getting to sleep last night and my mind kept returning to games that I&amp;rsquo;d call &lt;em>classic&lt;/em>. I was born in 1987, so my definition will most likely differ from yours. Also, after finishing this list I realized that my brain got stuck on violent games. There&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of classic games left that I&amp;rsquo;m not going to talk about here.&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">&lt;/nav>

&lt;h2 id="resident-evil-2-1998">Resident Evil 2 (1998)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With the release of Resident Evil 2 Remake, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but enforce the &lt;strong>1998&lt;/strong> whenever I mention this game. I really enjoyed the remake, but it will never take the place of the original game (other than Resident Evil Remake, which you&amp;rsquo;ll find further down).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Devil's Hour - Season 1 (2022)</title><link>/posts/the-devils-hour-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 20:48:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-devils-hour-2022/</guid><description>&lt;aside>&lt;p>&lt;p>Warning!!!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This contains heavy spoilers for the tv show.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Actually, I would say that knowing almost &lt;strong>anything&lt;/strong> about this is a spoiler. So if you think you might like this, give it a go and come back once you&amp;rsquo;ve watched it! 游뗵&lt;/p>
&lt;/p>&lt;/aside>

&lt;p>These six one-hour episodes are a wild ride that is worth experiencing. And they are worth being experienced without any prior knowledge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main focus of this show is Lucy Chambers, a single mom with a kid that is seemingly plagued by schizophrenia and is suffering from some type of autism. Isaac, the little boy, is unable to experience or express any feelings, although he is well able to differentiate them in others.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nightmare Frames (2022)</title><link>/posts/nightmare-frames-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 19:42:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/nightmare-frames-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Nightmare Frames&lt;/strong> by &lt;em>Postmodern Adventures&lt;/em> might be one of the best Lovecraftian horror games I&amp;rsquo;ve played so far.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It starts out as a pretty slow burn, but that&amp;rsquo;s alright for the horror genre. Once it&amp;rsquo;s got it&amp;rsquo;s hooks into you, it becomes really hard to put down. With two kids and a daytime job, I only get a few hours to myself every evening. If not for that, I can guarantee that I would have finished this in a single sitting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Halloween is coming up</title><link>/posts/halloween-is-coming-up/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 22:31:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/halloween-is-coming-up/</guid><description>&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">&lt;/nav>

&lt;h2 id="preamble">Preamble&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Every few years when halloween approaches I get the urge to (re)watch a whole bunch of scary movies. I&amp;rsquo;m not really picky so anything goes: slashers, elevated horror, ghost flicks, cosmic horror, &amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This year started out with a weird urge to rewatch all the &lt;em>Friday the 13th&lt;/em> movies. I looked up the entire franchise and couldn&amp;rsquo;t remember if I had seen the latest reboot. I&amp;rsquo;m honestly still not quite sure, but I thiiiiink I&amp;rsquo;ve seen it once before, so this marks my second go through all of these horrible movies. Sorry for spoiling my opinion beforehand. 游땦&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Upgrade (2018)</title><link>/posts/upgrade-2018/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 22:31:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/upgrade-2018/</guid><description>&lt;p>Someone wrote in to mention this movie in one of the latest WOFF dispatch episodes I&amp;rsquo;ve heard. Whoever wrote in compared it to &lt;em>Venom&lt;/em> and that is actually spot on. This movie is also brilliant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A violent mugging leaves a mechanic as a quadroplegic and without a wife. He decides to go through with an experimental operation that will implant STEM, an AI that can control his body into his spine. Together they take revenge on the muggers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>As Above, So Below (2014)</title><link>/posts/as-above-so-below-2014/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 21:09:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/as-above-so-below-2014/</guid><description>&lt;p>Just because I watched &lt;a href="../the-descent-2005">&lt;em>The Descent&lt;/em>&lt;/a> yesterday and it reminded me of this movie, I had to watch it again. I could remember almost nothing about this and was quite surprised at the &lt;em>Tomb Raider&lt;/em>-esque treasure hunting setup.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>The Descent&lt;/em>&amp;rsquo;s setup feels a bit more natural, as does most of that movie. &lt;em>As Above, So Below&lt;/em> is a found footage type movie, which I also completely forgot. It is more a gimmick than strictly necessary for any scares or suspense. I think in fact that &lt;strong>not&lt;/strong> being a found footage movie, might have helped the suspense as it could leave the audience guessing what&amp;rsquo;s real and what the characters might have imagined. Having an objective camera, at least for me, suggests that everything happens exactly as we see it. It also begs the question who recovers all the footage, because some of the cameras definately get left behind.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Descent (2005)</title><link>/posts/the-descent-2005/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 21:02:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-descent-2005/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a de(s)cent movie! 游때&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I always get this mixed up with &lt;a href="../as-above-so-below-2014">&lt;em>As Above, So Below&lt;/em>&lt;/a>, mostly because I know that both movies take place in caves. Whereas I had seen &lt;em>As Above, So Below&lt;/em> before, &lt;em>The Descent&lt;/em> was a new experience for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The film tells the story of an all female group of friends that go caving together. During the trip they find out that they are not as close knit friends as they thought they were.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unpacking (2021)</title><link>/posts/unpacking-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 22:25:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/unpacking-2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is an amazing game with lots of heart. And very relaxing. As the title suggest you&amp;rsquo;re unpacking moving boxes and placing the unpacked items in absolutely beautiful pixel-art rooms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Coming fresh off of &lt;strong>Return to Monkey Island&lt;/strong> I clicked through the first few stages very quickly. But even so I started placing items more deliberately and grouping matching objects (e.g. books) together. I also quickly noticed recurring items, which the unnamed (and unseen) person keeps between places.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Return to Monkey Island (2022)</title><link>/posts/return-to-monkey-island-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 21:13:57 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/return-to-monkey-island-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s something I didn&amp;rsquo;t think we&amp;rsquo;d ever get: a new Monkey Island from Ron Gilbert. And as expected it fits in perfectly with the first two Monkey Island games.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My first contact with the Monkey Island series was with &lt;strong>The Curse of Monkey Island&lt;/strong>. I did not know at that time that it was the third entry in the series, but I remember enjoying the humor and slapstick. I didn&amp;rsquo;t get much further than the second chapter as a kid, although I finished it sometime later with a walkthrough. I tried to get through it about a year or so ago, but got stuck again in the second chapter, although on a different problem. I distinctly remember solving that on my own as a kid, but for the life of me couldn&amp;rsquo;t remember the solution.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>