<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Stuff on Schafe sind bessere Rasenmäher</title><link>https://www.schafe-sind-bessere-rasenmaeher.de/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Stuff on Schafe sind bessere Rasenmäher</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 22:31:15 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.schafe-sind-bessere-rasenmaeher.de/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Upgrade (2018)</title><link>https://www.schafe-sind-bessere-rasenmaeher.de/posts/upgrade-2018/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 22:31:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.schafe-sind-bessere-rasenmaeher.de/posts/upgrade-2018/</guid><description>Someone wrote in to mention this movie in one of the latest WOFF dispatch episodes I&amp;rsquo;ve heard. Whoever wrote in compared it to Venom and that is actually spot on. This movie is also brilliant.
A violent mugging leaves a mechanic as a quadroplegic and without a wife. He decides to go through with an experimental operation that will implant STEM, an AI that can control his body into his spine.</description></item><item><title>As Above, So Below (2014)</title><link>https://www.schafe-sind-bessere-rasenmaeher.de/posts/as-above-so-below-2014/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 21:09:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.schafe-sind-bessere-rasenmaeher.de/posts/as-above-so-below-2014/</guid><description>Just because I watched The Descent yesterday and it reminded me of this movie, I had to watch it again. I could remember almost nothing about this and was quite surprised at the Tomb Raider-esque treasure hunting setup.
The Descent&amp;rsquo;s setup feels a bit more natural, as does most of that movie. As Above, So Below is a found footage type movie, which I also completely forgot. It is more a gimmick than strictly necessary for any scares or suspense.</description></item><item><title>The Descent (2005)</title><link>https://www.schafe-sind-bessere-rasenmaeher.de/posts/the-descent-2005/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 21:02:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.schafe-sind-bessere-rasenmaeher.de/posts/the-descent-2005/</guid><description>This is a de(s)cent movie! 😁
I always get this mixed up with As Above, So Below, mostly because I know that both movies take place in caves. Whereas I had seen As Above, So Below before, The Descent was a new experience for me.
The film tells the story of an all female group of friends that go caving together. During the trip they find out that they are not as close knit friends as they thought they were.</description></item><item><title>Unpacking (2021)</title><link>https://www.schafe-sind-bessere-rasenmaeher.de/posts/unpacking-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 22:25:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.schafe-sind-bessere-rasenmaeher.de/posts/unpacking-2021/</guid><description>This is an amazing game with lots of heart. And very relaxing. As the title suggest you&amp;rsquo;re unpacking moving boxes and placing the unpacked items in absolutely beautiful pixel-art rooms.
Coming fresh off of Return to Monkey Island I clicked through the first few stages very quickly. But even so I started placing items more deliberately and grouping matching objects (e.g. books) together. I also quickly noticed recurring items, which the unnamed (and unseen) person keeps between places.</description></item><item><title>Return to Monkey Island (2022)</title><link>https://www.schafe-sind-bessere-rasenmaeher.de/posts/return-to-monkey-island-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 21:13:57 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.schafe-sind-bessere-rasenmaeher.de/posts/return-to-monkey-island-2022/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s something I didn&amp;rsquo;t think we&amp;rsquo;d ever get: a new Monkey Island from Ron Gilbert. And as expected it fits in perfectly with the first two Monkey Island games.
My first contact with the Monkey Island series was with The Curse of Monkey Island. I did not know at that time that it was the third entry in the series, but I remember enjoying the humor and slapstick. I didn&amp;rsquo;t get much further than the second chapter as a kid, although I finished it sometime later with a walkthrough.</description></item></channel></rss>