<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Horror-Movies on Schafe sind bessere Rasenmäher</title><link>/tags/horror-movies/</link><description>Recent content in Horror-Movies on Schafe sind bessere Rasenmäher</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 21:09:38 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/horror-movies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>As Above, So Below (2014)</title><link>/posts/as-above-so-below-2014/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 21:09:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/as-above-so-below-2014/</guid><description>&lt;p>Just because I watched &lt;a href="../the-descent-2005">&lt;em>The Descent&lt;/em>&lt;/a> yesterday and it reminded me of this movie, I had to watch it again. I could remember almost nothing about this and was quite surprised at the &lt;em>Tomb Raider&lt;/em>-esque treasure hunting setup.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>The Descent&lt;/em>&amp;rsquo;s setup feels a bit more natural, as does most of that movie. &lt;em>As Above, So Below&lt;/em> is a found footage type movie, which I also completely forgot. It is more a gimmick than strictly necessary for any scares or suspense. I think in fact that &lt;strong>not&lt;/strong> being a found footage movie, might have helped the suspense as it could leave the audience guessing what&amp;rsquo;s real and what the characters might have imagined. Having an objective camera, at least for me, suggests that everything happens exactly as we see it. It also begs the question who recovers all the footage, because some of the cameras definately get left behind.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Descent (2005)</title><link>/posts/the-descent-2005/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 21:02:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-descent-2005/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a de(s)cent movie! 😁&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I always get this mixed up with &lt;a href="../as-above-so-below-2014">&lt;em>As Above, So Below&lt;/em>&lt;/a>, mostly because I know that both movies take place in caves. Whereas I had seen &lt;em>As Above, So Below&lt;/em> before, &lt;em>The Descent&lt;/em> was a new experience for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The film tells the story of an all female group of friends that go caving together. During the trip they find out that they are not as close knit friends as they thought they were.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>