<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tech on Schafe sind bessere Rasenmäher</title><link>/categories/tech/</link><description>Recent content in Tech on Schafe sind bessere Rasenmäher</description><generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 20:56:12 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>.NET Framework and Code Coverage from the Terminal with OpenCover</title><link>/tech/net-framework-and-code-coverage-from-the-terminal/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 20:56:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>/tech/net-framework-and-code-coverage-from-the-terminal/</guid><description>This is a condensed version of https://sbytestream.pythonanywhere.com/blog/Code-Coverage-For-NUnit . Many thanks Siddharth Barman, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have gotten this far without you.
Be advised that the OpenCover project has been archived and is no longer actively developed. There are FOSS alternatives available, but this is what I got working, so I&amp;rsquo;ll stick with it until it breaks.
I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to move most of my development workflows to the terminal. However, one of the last few things that&amp;rsquo;s been missing in my toolbelt, was gathering code coverage.</description></item><item><title>Gaming on Linux</title><link>/tech/gaming-on-linux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 12:59:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>/tech/gaming-on-linux/</guid><description>This is the 3rd part of a series where I rant about how I ended up with Linux as my daily driver.
The other parts can be found here:
How I learned how to use a PC How I came to love Linux Gaming on Linux This whole series was inspired by From Windows Fidelity to Linux Liberty: My Computing Evolution, a blog post by SudoMistress.
The final piece I needed to take the plunge on daily driving Linux was gaming.</description></item><item><title>How I came to love Linux</title><link>/tech/how-i-came-to-love-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 16:05:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>/tech/how-i-came-to-love-linux/</guid><description>This is the 2nd part of a series where I rant about how I ended up with Linux as my daily driver.
The other parts can be found here:
How I learned how to use a PC How I came to love Linux Gaming on Linux This whole series was inspired by From Windows Fidelity to Linux Liberty: My Computing Evolution, a blog post by SudoMistress.
I can&amp;rsquo;t exactly remember the first time I heard about this mystical alternative OS Linux.</description></item><item><title>How I learned to use a PC</title><link>/tech/how-i-learned-to-use-a-pc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 12:41:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>/tech/how-i-learned-to-use-a-pc/</guid><description>This is the 1st part of a series where I rant about how I ended up with Linux as my daily driver.
The other parts can be found here:
How I learned how to use a PC How I came to love Linux Gaming on Linux This whole series was inspired by From Windows Fidelity to Linux Liberty: My Computing Evolution, a blog post by SudoMistress.
When I was 10, my mom decided that we too needed a PC in our household.</description></item><item><title>Miez Attack, or how I got a job with a game about shooting cats</title><link>/tech/miez-attack/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 20:07:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>/tech/miez-attack/</guid><description>Back in 2015, after I had graduated from university, I was looking for jobs. I had a major in Physics, but my heart was no longer in it. Instead I wanted to write computer programs. After writing countless applications and receiving a few rejections (and a whole bunch of nothing), I finally hit a breakthrough. A small local company was willing to invite me for an interview.
It was in August of 2015, which I remember very well, because it was an incredibly hot day and I came fully armored in a suit1.</description></item><item><title>Building a client-server application with Akka.NET</title><link>/tech/building-a-client-server-app-with-akka-net/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 20:07:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>/tech/building-a-client-server-app-with-akka-net/</guid><description>Why I&amp;rsquo;m doing what I&amp;rsquo;m doing About a week ago or so, the QA guys at work asked me if I could help them out a bit. The test scenario required deploying a cluster of VMs running our product and putting some load on it. After a short outburst from my side (&amp;ldquo;HOW THE HELL DO YOU NOT DOCUMENT THE WAY YOU TEST THINGS!?&amp;rdquo;) we got talking about a cool manager like application where we would be able to coordinate multiple clients running different load generators.</description></item><item><title>How I inherited an Open Source project</title><link>/tech/how-i-inherited-an-open-source-project/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 21:07:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>/tech/how-i-inherited-an-open-source-project/</guid><description>On Monday the 6th February of 2023, I woke up to find a surprising email in my inbox.
An email with the subject RE: Chord Generator What is a Chord Generator?! Let&amp;rsquo;s go back a little in history&amp;hellip;
Back in 2017 I remember talking to my boss at work about GitHub. I mentioned, that I had a GitHub account, but at that time I only had one project uploaded and otherwise not interacted with it.</description></item><item><title>How I accidentally corrupted my WSL virtual disk and what I learned from it</title><link>/tech/corrupted-my-wsl-virtual-disk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 21:07:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>/tech/corrupted-my-wsl-virtual-disk/</guid><description>I love WSL. I mainly develop for Linux systems at work, but for company reasons am forced to use a Windows machine. WSL is the next best thing and I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending almost my entire time the last few years inside this sweet Linux environment.
A few days ago however, I managed to almost destroy my WSL instance. It took me a while to figure out what exactly happened, but here it goes.</description></item><item><title>I toot with the power of cURL</title><link>/tech/i-toot-with-the-power-of-curl/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 20:56:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>/tech/i-toot-with-the-power-of-curl/</guid><description>I spent the last two days trying to make a simple script that toots a static message on Mastodon. The idea came to me, because my instance admin is determined to welcome all new users to the instance. He&amp;rsquo;s been using the same message for a while, but when asked he admited that he puts them together manually every time.
As I&amp;rsquo;m not familiar with administrating a Mastodon instance, I offered to help in automating the part of the process sending out a welcome toot.</description></item><item><title>Docker builds are not reproducible</title><link>/tech/docker-builds-are-not-reproducible/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 21:30:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>/tech/docker-builds-are-not-reproducible/</guid><description>TL;DR
If your Docker build depends on installing packages from an external package repository, you might be in for a surprise.
A possible solution is to copy cached layers from an existing machine to a new one.
I&amp;rsquo;ll probably out myself as an absolute idiot, but Docker builds are far from reproducible.
Recently I had to setup a new Jenkins node at work and to verify that everything works correctly, I ran our build process.</description></item></channel></rss>