<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Children on Schafe sind bessere Rasenmäher</title><link>/tags/children/</link><description>Recent content in Children on Schafe sind bessere Rasenmäher</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 12:09:38 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/children/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mindful Parenting #2</title><link>/mindfulness/mindful-parenting-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 12:09:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>/mindfulness/mindful-parenting-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Things I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed so far:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I&amp;rsquo;m often annoyed when my kids want to talk to me. I&amp;rsquo;m usually already doing something else.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I&amp;rsquo;m more open to pay attention to my younger son. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s favoritism, although things are definitely easier with him. He plays a lot by himself and is more emotionally balanced&amp;hellip;for now.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No matter how hard I try, there will be times where I simply cannot attend to my kids. Work needs to be done, bills paid, groceries need to be bought and prepared. Not everything can happen when the kids are in bed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A bit ashamed that I only think about this now, but I&amp;rsquo;ve known for a long time that I&amp;rsquo;m susceptible to the emotions of other people. My older son becomes angry very quickly right now and that triggers me.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Things I can do:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mindful Parenting #1</title><link>/mindfulness/mindful-parenting-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 21:09:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>/mindfulness/mindful-parenting-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been angry a lot these last few weeks. I&amp;rsquo;ve been carrying a great big burning ball of anger inside me that threatens to burst out. Occasionally it does, too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My older child is now about 4.5 years old. He&amp;rsquo;s craving autonomy and control. Control over everything: his body, his parents, his brother, his surroundings&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s maddening. He does so many small things that drive me &lt;strong>crazy&lt;/strong>!!!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rediscovering the Hungarian language with a children's book</title><link>/posts/rediscovering-the-hungarian-language/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 21:09:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/rediscovering-the-hungarian-language/</guid><description>&lt;p>2023 hasn&amp;rsquo;t been a big reading year for me. I tend to alternate very heavily between watching movies and tv shows, playing videogames and reading books. This year I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing a lot of videogames with what little free time I have.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nevertheless, I do have a candidate for my &lt;em>book of the year 2023&lt;/em>: &lt;strong>A majom mamája&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;figure>
 &lt;img src="cover.webp" alt="The cover for A majom mamája." />
 &lt;figcaption>The cover for A majom mamája.&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>